ILGWU Sol Chaikin Photographs 5780/083 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Sol Chaikin Photographs
1940-1989
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Chaikin, Sol C.
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/083 P
1.61 cubic feet
1.6 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection contains photographs of Sol Chaikin at a variety of events, including conventions, meetings, and rallies. Also included are photographs of ILGWU groups and institutions, political figures, and other events.
7128471
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 15, 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 03, 2015
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Sol Chaikin was born in New York City January 9th, 1918. He graduated from Townsend Harris Hall High School in 1934. In 1940 he married Rosalind Bryon. Chaikin received a LL.B Degree from Brooklyn Law School. He then became an Organizer for the ILGWU, Local 178 in Fall River Massachusetts.
Chaikin held many union jobs through his lifetime.
1942-Business Agent, Local 281, Boston and Lowell, Massachusetts; 1943-U.S. Air Force; 1946-Manager, Local 22, ILGWU, Springfield, Massachusetts and Manager, Western Mass. District, Northeast Dept., ILGWU; 1955-Director, Lower Southwest Region, ILGWU; 1959-Assistant Director, Northeast Dept., ILGWU; 1965-Vice President, ILGWU; 1968-Chairman, American Trade Union Council for Histadrut; 1969-Associate Trustee, Long Island Jewish Hillside Medical Center; 1973-General Secretary-Treasurer, ILGWU; Vice-President, AFL-CIO Industrial Union Dept. Member, Board of Directors, New York Urban Coalition; 1975-President, ILGWU; Vice-President, AFL-CIO and Member, Executive Council Member, Governor's Task Force on Housing; 1976-Delegate to Democratic National Convention; Trade Union Council for Histadrut; 1977-Labor Representative, Belgrade Conference to Review Helsinki Accord on Human Rights; Head of AFL-CIO Delegation to International Labor Summit, London; Received Labor Human Rights Award, Jewish Labor Committee; 1978-Received Townsend Harris Award; Member, U.S. Delegation to Attend Funeral of Prime Minister Golda Meir; 1979-Present At Signing of Israel-Egypt Peace Treaty at the White House; 1980-Member, U.S. Delegation to ILO Session in Geneva; Vice-Chair, N.Y. Convention Center Operating Corp.; Member, Board of Trustees, Brandeis University; Honorary Degrees from Rutgers University and City University of New York; Seconded the Nomination of President Carter, Democratic National Convention; Published, A Labor Viewpoint: Another Opinion; 1982-Head, AFL-CIO Fact- Finding Mission to South Africa; Member, N.Y.S. Governor's Special Transit Advisory Panel; 1983-Hosted ZENSEN Delegation from Japan for Discussions of Apparel and Textile Industries; 1986-Retired as President of the ILGWU.
Sol Chaikin died April 1, 1991 at the age of 73.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/083: ILGWU Sol Chaikin Papers 5780/083 AV: ILGWU Sol Chaikin Audio-Visual Materials 5780/135: ILGWU Sol C. Chaikin "The First Year, 1975-1976" Presentation Volume
Women's clothing industry--United States; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing trade--United States.; Chaikin, Sol C.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Southeast Region
7128471
- AFL-CIO (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abel, I.W. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Argentina (Human Rights) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Awards/Honors (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Beame, Abe (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Brown, Jerry (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bush, George (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cambria County (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Carter, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Carter, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Carter, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Carter, Jimmy--Inauguration (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Carter, Jimmy--nomination by Chaikin (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Carter, Jimmy--meetings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Carter, Jimmy--meetings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chaikin and family--early years (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chaikin and family--early years (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Chaikin and family--early years (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chaikin and family--early years (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chaikin, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chaikin, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Chaikin, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Chaikin, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Chaikin, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Chaikin, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Chaikin (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Chaikin--retirement, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Chile, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Civil Rights (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Conventions, 1968-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Conventions, 1968-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Conventions, 1968-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Conventions, 1968-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Cuomo, Mario (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Deborah Dinner (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Democratic Convention, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Dubinsky, David (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Dukakis, Michael (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Fall River, Massachusetts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Finley, Murray (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Foreign Heads of State (Box 2, Folder 17)
- General Secretary-Treasurer (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Hall, Paul (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Histadrut (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Humphrey, Hubert (Box 2, Folder 21)
- International Labour Organization, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Imports Legislation--Testimony (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Interviews (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Japan Summit, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Kennedy, John F. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Kenned, Ted (Box 2, Folder 27)
- King, Coretta S. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Koch, Ed (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Labor Mass (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Labor Summit, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Lincoln Center (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Locals (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Locals (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Locals (Box 3, Folder 1)
- London (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Meany, George (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Milano, Ed (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mondale, Walter (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Moynihan, Daniel (Box 3, Folder 6)
- New York State AFL-CIO (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Northeast (Lower Southwest), 1956-1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- O'Neill, Tip (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Peru (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Political Rallies (Box 3, Folder 11)
- President, Swearing in of, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- President--Portraits (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Rabin (Ambassador of Israel) (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Randolph, A. Philip (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Rizzo, Frank (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Rockefeller Center--Fashion Show (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Rome, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Schmidt, Helmut--Dinner (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Shapp, Milton (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Social Democrats (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Stolberg Hospital Ceremony (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Street Fair, New York City (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Tennessee (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Truman, Harry S. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Union Label (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Unity House (Box 3, Folder 27)
- White House, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- White House, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- White House, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 31)
- 12 oversize photos sorted out of the 'misc. photos' box stored over the mapcase (Box 55, Folder 1)